Willy Garabini Cornelissen





MASTER RESEARCH

"A Survey of Machine Learning applied to a Music Information Research(MIR) task: Onset Detection"

Machine Learning is being applied in many areas with excellent results actually, including audio and music (MIR - Music Information Retrieval). The work done to get my master degree deals with the automatic detection of musical onsets and the investigation of the applicability of machine learning. Many MIR tasks are showing a lot of benefits using this new data paradigm.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAN 2016 - OCT 2016 (FT)

Zunnit Sistemas Inteligentes **Software Engineer**

Analysis and development of machine learning solutions, using Python and JAVA.

FEB 2011 - NOV 2014 (FT)

SENAC-MS *Teacher*

Instruction and teaching on many extension courses: JAVA, PHP, SCRUM, Database Management and Development Frameworks.

APR 2005 - DEC 2010 (PT)

IBM

JAVA Developer

Involved on many development teams, working on IBM's clients in diverse fields: supply chain, CRM, Automatic Translation and Web development.

FEB 2002 - DEC 2004 (PT)

TRE-MG **PHP Developer**

PHP Development for the elections of 2002 and 2004 in Brasil.

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Haytheon

POSITION C++ Developer

PROJECT SIVAM - System of Surveillance of Amazon

IBM USA

POSITION C++ Developer

PROJECT AMMS - Anthem Medical Management System

EDUCATION

2018 - NOW Master of Artificial Intelligence

Escola de Música

Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais

1992-2000 Departamento de Ciência da Computação

UNIVERSIDADE FEDERAL DE MINAS GERAIS

1989 – 1992 **Technician**

INFORMÁTICA INDUSTRIAL

CEFET-MG

CERTIFICATIONS

2017 Neural Networks for Machine Learning

Coursera

2016 Introduction to Natural Language Processing

Coursera

2016 Machine Learning

Coursera

2016 Learning with Scikit-Learn

DataCamp

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING Python, JAVA, PHP, Javascript

FRAMEWORKS Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, Scipy

DEVELOPMENT Machine/Deep Learning, UML, IS

FIELDS MIR, Bioinformatics, NLP

PUBLICATIONS

Cornelissen, W. G., Loureiro, M. A. (A ser publicada). Detecção de onsets usando o aprendizado de máquina *Dissertação*, Belo Horizonte, MG.

Cornelissen, W. G., Loureiro, M. A. (2019). Detecção automática do início de notas usando o aprendizado de máquina *ANPPOM*, Pelotas, RS.

Cornelissen, W. G., Loureiro, M. A. (2019). Automatic onset detection using convolutional neural networks. *SBCM*, São João del Rei, MG.

Endereço Lattes: http://lattes.cnpq.br/5686440703188985